<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maxwell Jensen&#39;s Website on </title>
    <link>https://maxwelljensen.eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Maxwell Jensen&#39;s Website on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://maxwelljensen.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tutoring at Noroff</title>
      <link>https://maxwelljensen.eu/experience/job-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxwelljensen.eu/experience/job-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People with digital competence and creativity are in extraordinary high&#xA;demand. Many of today&amp;rsquo;s jobs will disappear, and far too few job applicants&#xA;have the knowledge and skills to cover the industry&amp;rsquo;s current and future needs.&#xA;People’s skill sets need to be developed, and education is the solution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Noroff is the premier academic institution in the Nordics for IT, both at&#xA;university and vocational level. In my time there, I have seen that there were&#xA;many capable teachers and students.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First job</title>
      <link>https://maxwelljensen.eu/experience/job-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxwelljensen.eu/experience/job-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Processing and archiving of shipment bills, correction of shipment errors, help&#xA;on the conveyor belt, and general assistance at the office.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux course showcase</title>
      <link>https://maxwelljensen.eu/lnx_course_showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxwelljensen.eu/lnx_course_showcase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maxwelljensen.eu/lcs/lnx_course_showcase1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maxwelljensen.eu/lcs/lnx_course_showcase2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maxwelljensen.eu/lcs/lnx_course_showcase3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noroff</title>
      <link>https://maxwelljensen.eu/client-work/noroff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxwelljensen.eu/client-work/noroff/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The educational Linux course</title>
      <link>https://maxwelljensen.eu/projects/lnx_course/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxwelljensen.eu/projects/lnx_course/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my tenure as tutor at Noroff vocational online school, I was tasked by&#xA;my team leader to recreate the Linux course &amp;ndash; part of the Network and System&#xA;Administration program &amp;ndash; in order to modernise it; make it more digestible for&#xA;students. The course I inherited, and went through myself as a student, was&#xA;getting crusty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After close to &lt;strong&gt;eleven months of continuous work&lt;/strong&gt;, I managed to create a&#xA;five-week-long course, for full-time studies, that consisted of purely&#xA;original:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internet Death</title>
      <link>https://maxwelljensen.eu/blog/internet_death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxwelljensen.eu/blog/internet_death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Internet is a mega entertainment complex built on top of a graveyard of&#xA;meaning. Only Silicon Valley-approved content, opinions, and mechanisms may be&#xA;used to do anything on the Internet. I talk a bit about how the Internet has&#xA;been slowly choked out and how it is now dead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am not particularly old. BBS, Usenet, MUDs and other such 1990s constructs&#xA;were not part of my childhood, but I still got to explore some of the wild&#xA;Internet of the early 2000s. Practically speaking, it was like entering&#xA;international waters. Seemingly no rules applied, and no law held dominion.&#xA;This was the case for many years, far before the start of the 21st century,&#xA;although of course the Internet did not get substantially bigger until this&#xA;century.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Programming Languages</title>
      <link>https://maxwelljensen.eu/blog/programming_langs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxwelljensen.eu/blog/programming_langs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of programming languages, but often they are talked of in terms of what realistic applications they&#xA;have in the job market. Seldom is there prose about their quality as such; independent of their popularity and&#xA;application. Here&amp;rsquo;s some of my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;quality-versus-utility&#34;&gt;Quality versus utility&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As most software engineers know, there is not really any correlation between the quality of a language and its&#xA;popularity. There is however a correlation between popularity and utility. Python might not be the best language ever&#xA;made, but any design flaws it has are offset, in the eyes of most, by the fact that it has libraries for everything.&#xA;Why? Because it is in top three most popular languages, somewhere around C and Java. Therefore any issue one might&#xA;encounter probably already has a complete solution in the form of a third-party library. This means that Python has&#xA;extremely high utility, even if there are design issues with the language that can get in the way of common usage;&#xA;while writing code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
