<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maxwell Jensen&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://maxwelljensen.eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Maxwell Jensen&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://maxwelljensen.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Internet Death</title>
      <link>https://maxwelljensen.eu/posts/internet_death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxwelljensen.eu/posts/internet_death/</guid>
      <description>The Internet is a mega entertainment complex built on top of a graveyard of meaning. Only Silicon Valley-approved content, opinions, and mechanisms may be used to do anything on the Internet. I talk a bit about how the Internet has been slowly choked out and how it is now dead.&#xA;I am not particularly old. BBS, Usenet, MUDs and other such 1990s constructs were not part of my childhood, but I still got to explore some of the wild Internet of the early 2000s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Programming Languages</title>
      <link>https://maxwelljensen.eu/posts/programming_langs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxwelljensen.eu/posts/programming_langs/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of programming languages, but often they are talked of in terms of what realistic applications they have in the job market. Seldom is there prose about their quality as such; independent of their popularity and application. Here&amp;rsquo;s some of my thoughts.&#xA;Quality versus utility As most software engineers know, there is not really any correlation between the quality of a language and its popularity. There is however a correlation between popularity and utility.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Licensing for Beginners</title>
      <link>https://maxwelljensen.eu/posts/licensing_for_beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxwelljensen.eu/posts/licensing_for_beginners/</guid>
      <description>The most fundamental, yet seriously overlooked, aspect of any software is licensing. Whether we like it or not, the fact is that anything we create or want to use is subject to copyright. Worst of all, legal illiteracy is a major issue in the free and open source software (FOSS) sphere. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to correctly licence your software, and what licensing means to begin with.&#xA;Disclaimer: This article is not legal advice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://maxwelljensen.eu/index-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maxwelljensen.eu/index-about/</guid>
      <description>My hobbies and passion are in programming, history, philosophy, and culture, just to name a few. This is my website to publish posts for the world to read. Occasionally I have programming projects, which you can check out on my GitHub. If you have questions or want to come into contact with me for any other reason, you may do so at maxwelljensen@posteo.net.&#xA;I do a blog, which you are viewing right now, where I post about various topics from time to time.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
